Guide to the Joe Nash Collection, 1946-1999 ADF.011
American Dance Festival Archives
Joe Nash collection
1946-1999
American Dance Festival Archives
Nash, Joe
ADF.011
0.21 Linear Feet
Joe Nash (1919-2005) was a self-taught dancer and prominent historian of African-American dance history. Collection includes photographic prints, programs, clippings, fliers, and other printed materials.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Please contact the American Dance Festival Archives (adf@americandancefestival.org) to arrange for use of these materials.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Acquisitions Information
The Joe Nash Collection was received as a gift.
Biographical Note
Joe Nash (1919-2005) was a self-taught dancer and prominent historian of African-American dance history. Growing up in New York City during the Harlem Renaissance, Nash was inspired by the black arts movement. After returning from his World War II military service, he immersed himself in a self-directed study of dance literature and photography. In the late 1940s and '50s, Nash performed on Broadway and toured with influential modern dance artists such as Pearl Primus and Donald McKayle. He also began teaching and lecturing on dance history in Philadelphia and New York. Nash was a consultant and lecturer at the American Dance Festival from the 1990s until his death in 2005. He was widely considered one of the leading experts on the role of African-Americans in the development of modern dance. During his life, Nash donated materials from his vast archival collection to the New York Public Library, the Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture in Harlem, The Arthur Hall Collection in Philadelphia, Florida A&M University, the American Dance Festival, and the National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center in Ohio.
Collection Overview
Collection includes photographic prints, programs, clippings, fliers, and other printed materials.
Nash, Joe.
- Printed Materials, 1946-1999 and undated
  - Printed materials about Joe Nash, 1988-1999
  - Pioneers in Negro Concert Dance by Joe Nash in Dance Women/Living Legends
  - Dancing Many Drums by Joe Nash in National Scene Magazine Supplement, Sept./Oct. 1976
  - Talking Drums! The Journal of Black Dance, A Memorial Tribute to Alvin Ailey, May, 1990
  - Joe Nash resumes
  - Theater Grottesco and Rennie Harris Puremovement at The New Victory Theater program, 1999
  - Ruth Page Awards and Benefit program, 1998
  - Ruth St. Denis with Ted Shawn program
  - Pearl Primus and Group program, 1946
  - Donald McKayle and Company program, 1956
  - Jacob's Pillow Festival program, 1954
  - Barton Mumaw publicity
  - Martha Graham publicity
  - Valerie Bettis photograph
  - Diane McIntyre photograph, 1979
  - 100 Poster Masterpieces auction catalog, 1981